Cevat Enes Karaahmetoğlu

Ankara, Turkey

cevateness@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/cevat-enes-

Summary

I am an optimization scientist focused on developing robust mathematical models and algorithms to deliver efficient solutions for challenging decision problems, primarily within the domains of supply chain, logistics, and transportation.

In my master's thesis, I conducted an in-depth study on the collaborative consolidation of shipments among shippers with varying characteristics, with a special focus on inventory costs and cooperation.

With three years of experience as a production planning engineer, I have honed my skills in scheduling and supply chain planning. During this time, I gained valuable insights into the significance of sustainable business processes, the importance of accurate data collection, and the ability to extract meaningful insights from data analysis. These experiences have ingrained in me the ability to make informed decisions and strive for optimal outcomes.

Experience



Optimization Scientist

Optiyol | AI for Transportation

Sep 2021 - Present (2 years 6 months)

My primary focus is on developing solutions to the following decision problems:

- Last-mile delivery network design
- Middle-mile delivery optimization and transportation planning
- Crew, order, container loading and shift assignment
- A wide variety of vehicle routing problems, including those with time intervals, open routes, and pickup and delivery scenarios.

Additionally, I leverage data science techniques and statistical analysis to enhance these solutions. I employ predictive algorithms, clustering methods, and heuristics to enhance optimization models through both pre- and post-processing stages, enabling data-informed decision-making.



Senior Production Planning Engineer

Roketsan

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021 (3 months)



Production Planning Engineer

Roketsan

Jul 2018 - Jul 2021 (3 years 1 month)

- Worked on workshop scheduling and managing supply chain activities according to deadlines and priorities.
- Worked as a functional analyst on implementation of scheduling software in capacity planning, shift arrangement and detailed scheduling software for optimized decision making.

• Worked in a simulation team for modelling of different type of workshops for scenario analysis and capacity planning considering with specific constraints.

Argella System Design Team Member

Arçelik Global

Sep 2017 - Jun 2018 (10 months)

Improving the Acceptance Process in Incoming Materials Logistics in Arçelik Cooking Appliances Plant in Bolu.

Our main focus in this project was "Improving the utilization rates of ramps, the average waiting time of the trucks by rearranging the schedules of the incoming trucks and reassignment of ramps to specific raw materials and trucks by considering the emergency of the raw materials and constraints of suppliers, ramps, the ramping and storage areas."

Intern

Aselsan

Jul 2017 - Aug 2017 (2 months)

Production Planning Department

- -Worked on the layout and the material flow process of the warehouse to decrease the congestion and make the material acceptance and delivery processes more efficient.
- -Supported research and development efforts for mathematical model of production planning problem.

CO-OP Intern

Turkish Aerospace

Jun 2016 - Aug 2016 (3 months)

Capacity Planning Department

-Worked on medium and long term capacity planning studies of a newly established production facility considering resource, time and space constraints.

Education

() Orta Doğu Teknik Üniversitesi / Middle East Technical University

Master's degree, Industrial Engineering

Sep 2019 - Nov 2022

MS Thesis:

The Price of Anarchy in an Uncapacitated Deterministic Shipment Consolidation Game

Hacettepe University

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Industrial Engineering

Oct 2023 - Present

Interests:

Multi Criteria Decision Making

Combinatorial Optimization

Data Mining

Decision Analytics

Orta Doğu Teknik Üniversitesi / Middle East Technical University
Bachelor's degree, Industrial Engineering
2013 - 2018

Licenses & Certifications

- **Machine Learning A-Z™: Hands-On Python In Data Science** Udemy
- in Python Object-Oriented Programming LinkedIn
- in Python Essential Training LinkedIn
- kaggle Intermediate Machine Learning Kaggle
- kaggle Data Visualization Kaggle
- SQL for Data Science Coursera

 DKNQGXYLRMUQ

Skills

Operations Research • Optimization • Mathematical Modeling • Supply Chain Management • Problem Solving • Research • Production Planning • Git • Data Visualization • Programming